QUESTIONS = [
  {
    "question": "As individuals, we worry --- about collective survival?",
    "options": {
      "A": "more",
      "B": "often",
      "C": "less",
      "D": "regularly"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },

  {
    "question": "The word “sociology” was first conceived about 1838 by the French social thinker, ___________.",
    "answer": "Auguste Comte",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sociology is the scientific study of the behaviour of human beings in ___________ society.",
    "answer": "group",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  
  {
    "question": "Humans are able to harness and control the forces of nature through?",
    "options": {
      "A": "personal opinions",
      "B": "education",
      "C": "modern technology",
      "D": "interaction"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A precarious working relationship which is overshadowed by latent conflict is called?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Andragonistic Cooperation",
      "B": "Antagonism Cooperation",
      "C": "Catagonistic Cooperation",
      "D": "Antagonistic Cooperation"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "is brought about by a third party whose resolution of the conflict is accepted by the contending parties?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Harbitration",
      "B": "Arbitration",
      "C": "Arbitation",
      "D": "Farbitration"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },

  {
    "question": "A society may be defined as a set of men (human beings) in ___________.",
    "answer": "interdependence",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Great distances do not prevent the formation of a ___________ if there is agreement on objectives and recognised methods of understanding one another.",
    "answer": "society",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "In modern society, individuals have been placed comfortably away from the edge of ___________.",
    "answer": "survival",
    "type": "fill"
  },

  {
    "question": "A temporary agreement to cease active conflict for some period of time is?",
    "options": {
      "A": "resolution",
      "B": "truce",
      "C": "truth",
      "D": "tort"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "feminism, the youth movement, and labour movement are --- social movement?",
    "options": {
      "A": "immediate",
      "B": "specific",
      "C": "latent",
      "D": "general"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "All social movements are ?",
    "options": {
      "A": "act oriented",
      "B": "action-oriented",
      "C": "society oriented",
      "D": "human oriented"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },

  {
    "question": "Human beings must learn skills and have skills because they are not genetically ___________.",
    "answer": "programmed",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sociology is concerned with developing systematic and reliable knowledge about the ___________ of man and of society.",
    "answer": "behaviour",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sociology is generally regarded as a branch of the ___________ sciences.",
    "answer": "social",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The institution that develops as a consequence of the need to maintain social order in the society is?",
    "options": {
      "A": "management",
      "B": "population",
      "C": "government",
      "D": "society"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The process of acquiring and using power, and government is the ultimate source of legitimate power in society is?",
    "options": {
      "A": "politics",
      "B": "management",
      "C": "economy",
      "D": "history"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "What premise is the preoccupation with the welfare of the collectivity, with the whole society, rather than with the individual?",
    "options": {
      "A": "communism",
      "B": "Socialism",
      "C": "capitalism",
      "D": "economist"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The two broad subdivisions in forms of marriage are monogamy and?",
    "options": {
      "A": "endogamy",
      "B": "polygamy",
      "C": "exogamy",
      "D": "pologamy"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },

  {
    "question": "The sociologist’s viewpoint is basically one of ___________ rather than that of anger, resistance or faith.",
    "answer": "curiosity",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Destruction of what we call nature results in the ___________ of human society.",
    "answer": "destruction",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Modern technology provides man with tools to harness and ___________ the forces of nature.",
    "answer": "control",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sociology studies all forms of human ___________.",
    "answer": "interaction",
    "type": "fill"
  },

  {
    "question": "Banks, stock exchange, joint stock companies and courts are -- institutions?",
    "options": {
      "A": "enacted",
      "B": "coercive",
      "C": "societal",
      "D": "summer's"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The -- is the largest social group?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Society",
      "B": "System",
      "C": "Populace",
      "D": "Human beings"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The survival of the society depends on the -- of social institutions in the performance of their specialized functions?",
    "options": {
      "A": "e ficiency",
      "B": "e fectiveness",
      "C": "personality",
      "D": "approach"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Replacement of personnel or members when they die, leave or become incapacitated is a\tview?",
    "options": {
      "A": "principal",
      "B": "functionalist",
      "C": "societal",
      "D": "constitutional"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },

  {
    "question": "Sociology arose in societies where there are two or more ___________ of values.",
    "answer": "sets",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sociology could not arise in a society which assumes the claims of ___________.",
    "answer": "absolute truth",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sociology is morally a science of ___________.",
    "answer": "neutrality",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sociology deals with the origin, growth, structure and ___________ of human society.",
    "answer": "characteristics",
    "type": "fill"
  },

  {
    "question": "The simplest and largest class of society is?",
    "options": {
      "A": "hunting",
      "B": "agrarian",
      "C": "horticultural",
      "D": "preindustrial"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Society is classified by social organization into?",
    "options": {
      "A": "3",
      "B": "4",
      "C": "2",
      "D": "5"
    },
    "answer": "",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Technology made things feasible and?",
    "options": {
      "A": "attainable",
      "B": "a fordable",
      "C": "available",
      "D": "achievable"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },

  {
    "question": "Sociology is the scientific study of the behaviour of human beings in a ___________.",
    "answer": "group society",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The British sociologist Herbert Spencer was the propounder of ___________.",
    "answer": "Social Darwinism",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term “survival of the fittest” was introduced by ___________.",
    "answer": "Spencer",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine of human history is ___________.",
    "answer": "class conflict",
    "type": "fill"
  },

  {
    "question": "Natural destruction leads to\tdestruction?",
    "options": {
      "A": "society",
      "B": "future",
      "C": "standard",
      "D": "quality"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Society and person are?",
    "options": {
      "A": "interdependent",
      "B": "coexist",
      "C": "partners",
      "D": "dependent"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The formal aspect of socialization in which a specific body of knowledge and skills is deliberately transmitted by a crop of specialists js?",
    "options": {
      "A": "education",
      "B": "certificate",
      "C": "status",
      "D": "position"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "What offers the individual the needed support in critical stages of his growth and maturation?",
    "options": {
      "A": "religion",
      "B": "rituals",
      "C": "custom",
      "D": "belief"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A systemof beliefs and rituals dealing with the sacred is?",
    "options": {
      "A": "beliefs",
      "B": "trust",
      "C": "religion",
      "D": "a fection"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The union of one and with one woman is?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Polygamy",
      "B": "moxogamy",
      "C": "Monogamy",
      "D": "mologamy"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Those who own the means of production are called the ___________.",
    "answer": "Bourgeoisie",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Those who do not own the means of production and must sell their labour power are the ___________.",
    "answer": "Proletariat",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Durkheim’s classic study showed that groups with weaker social ties have ___________ suicide rates.",
    "answer": "higher",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Durkheim used the concept of ___________ to explain suicide.",
    "answer": "social integration",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The idea of linking Protestant ethics to the rise of capitalism was developed by ___________.",
    "answer": "Max Weber",
    "type": "fill"
  },

  {
    "question": "The two broad subdivisions in forms of marriage are monogamy and?",
    "options": {
      "A": "endogamy",
      "B": "polygamy",
      "C": "exogamy",
      "D": "pologamy"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Banks, stock exchange, joint stock companies and courts are -- institutions?",
    "options": {
      "A": "enacted",
      "B": "coercive",
      "C": "societal",
      "D": "summer's"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The -- is the largest social group?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Society",
      "B": "System",
      "C": "Populace",
      "D": "Human beings"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Parsons emphasised the need for developing ___________ models of society.",
    "answer": "abstract",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "C. Wright Mills emphasised the development of social ___________.",
    "answer": "imagination",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sociology helps us to assess the truth of commonly held ___________.",
    "answer": "assumptions",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "A sociologist sees general patterns in the behaviour of particular ___________.",
    "answer": "individuals",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Social location refers to a person’s ___________, income, education, gender or age.",
    "answer": "job",
    "type": "fill"
  },

  {
    "question": "The survival of the society depends on the -- of social institutions in the performance of their specialized functions?",
    "options": {
      "A": "e ficiency",
      "B": "e fectiveness",
      "C": "personality",
      "D": "approach"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Replacement of personnel or members when they die, leave or become incapacitated is a\tview?",
    "options": {
      "A": "principal",
      "B": "functionalist",
      "C": "societal",
      "D": "constitutional"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Economy, marriage and religion are\tinstitutions?",
    "options": {
      "A": "secondary",
      "B": "tertiary",
      "C": "society",
      "D": "primary"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The spread of culture traits fromone society to another, or fromone region or group to another within the same society is?",
    "options": {
      "A": "dilution",
      "B": "di fusion",
      "C": "ilusion",
      "D": "Farbitration"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The process whereby men acquire newfactual knowledge about empirical reality is called?",
    "options": {
      "A": "descovery",
      "B": "discovery",
      "C": "discover",
      "D": "discoveries"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Certain animal species-notably the social insects also form?",
    "options": {
      "A": "cities",
      "B": "association",
      "C": "group",
      "D": "societies"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The way of life of any society is?",
    "options": {
      "A": "law",
      "B": "culture",
      "C": "plans",
      "D": "task"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The institution that develops as a consequence of the need to maintain social order in the society is?",
    "options": {
      "A": "management",
      "B": "population",
      "C": "government",
      "D": "society"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The process of acquiring and using power, and government is the ultimate source of legitimate power in society is?",
    "options": {
      "A": "politics",
      "B": "management",
      "C": "economy",
      "D": "history"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "What premise is the preoccupation with the welfare of the collectivity, with the whole society, rather than with the individual?",
    "options": {
      "A": "communism",
      "B": "Socialism",
      "C": "capitalism",
      "D": "economist"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of -- was that an individual invested his property with expectation of accumulating more property through his own work and enterprise?",
    "options": {
      "A": "communism",
      "B": "socialism",
      "C": "capitalism",
      "D": "economist"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Capitalism,socialism and communism are three --- system?",
    "options": {
      "A": "economics",
      "B": "economic",
      "C": "economy",
      "D": "economist"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The first component of education is?",
    "options": {
      "A": "position",
      "B": "status",
      "C": "chance",
      "D": "change"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },

  {
    "question": "Scientific laws are universal statements of ___________.",
    "answer": "regularities",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Laws must not be ___________.",
    "answer": "accidental",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Social sciences aim to produce ___________ laws.",
    "answer": "general",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "A scientific explanation is usually a ___________ explanation.",
    "answer": "descriptive",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The historical approach is based on the classic writings of ___________.",
    "answer": "sociology",
    "type": "fill"
  },

  {
    "question": "People select the roles they consider?",
    "options": {
      "A": "important",
      "B": "special",
      "C": "mundane",
      "D": "perfect"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most important types of contemporary conflict are class and --- conflict?",
    "options": {
      "A": "race",
      "B": "tribe",
      "C": "racial",
      "D": "people"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A process in which individuals or group strive against each other for the use or ownership of limited goods is called?",
    "options": {
      "A": "confusion",
      "B": "opposition",
      "C": "conflict",
      "D": "war"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is absolute if only one of the contending parties can win?",
    "options": {
      "A": "protest",
      "B": "competition",
      "C": "conflict",
      "D": "interview"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Competition is --if each rival is not aware of the existence of his contenders?",
    "options": {
      "A": "impersonal",
      "B": "personal",
      "C": "predictable",
      "D": "infered"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "What prevails in small groups such as families and ethnic groups where little roomis left for the distinction?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Primary Cooperation",
      "B": "Primary Cooperative",
      "C": "Primary Control",
      "D": "Primary Connection"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A process in which individuals or groups work together to performa task or to reach a commonly valued goal is called?",
    "options": {
      "A": "connection",
      "B": "cooperation",
      "C": "man-pass-man",
      "D": "cooperative"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A temporary agreement to cease active conflict for some period of time is?",
    "options": {
      "A": "resolution",
      "B": "truce",
      "C": "truth",
      "D": "tort"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },

  {
    "question": "The empirical approach in sociology asks what contemporary ___________ are doing.",
    "answer": "sociologists",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The analytical approach divides the subject matter according to ___________.",
    "answer": "arbitrary reasoning",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sociology studies basic social institutions such as the family, religion, ___________ and the state.",
    "answer": "economic institutions",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fundamental social processes include differentiation and ___________.",
    "answer": "stratification",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sociology regards truth as ___________.",
    "answer": "relative",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "A precarious working relationship which is overshadowed by latent conflict is called?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Andragonistic Cooperation",
      "B": "Antagonism Cooperation",
      "C": "Catagonistic Cooperation",
      "D": "Antagonistic Cooperation"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "is brought about by a third party whose resolution of the conflict is accepted by the contending parties?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Harbitration",
      "B": "Arbitration",
      "C": "Arbitation",
      "D": "Farbitration"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A temporary agreement to cease active conflict for some period of time is?",
    "options": {
      "A": "resolution",
      "B": "truce",
      "C": "truth",
      "D": "tort"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "feminism, the youth movement, and labour movement are --- social movement?",
    "options": {
      "A": "immediate",
      "B": "specific",
      "C": "latent",
      "D": "general"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "All social movements are ?",
    "options": {
      "A": "act oriented",
      "B": "action-oriented",
      "C": "society oriented",
      "D": "human oriented"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The -- is described as having \ufffd??collective mind\ufffd?\ufffd and a psychic unity which change the normal behaviour of people into",
    "options": {
      "A": "people",
      "B": "population",
      "C": "crowd",
      "D": "society"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is represented by the momentary assemblage of individuals who watch a performer in the window of a store?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Casual Crowd",
      "B": "Mammoth Crowd",
      "C": "Popular Crowd",
      "D": "Casualities Crowd"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Many viewers of a television programme who are physically separated fromone another, but still witness the same event are -- crowd?",
    "options": {
      "A": "populated",
      "B": "di fused",
      "C": "mammoth",
      "D": "population"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "An imaginary model, or sociologist\ufffd??s conceptualization, of howsocial relationships work is called?",
    "options": {
      "A": "social class",
      "B": "social sub-system",
      "C": "social system",
      "D": "socialite system"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Social interaction occurs on -- levels of social organization?",
    "options": {
      "A": "two",
      "B": "three",
      "C": "four",
      "D": "five"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Husband to wife, father to son, teacher to student, girlfriend to boyfriend is an example of -- level?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Fourth",
      "B": "Third",
      "C": "Second",
      "D": "First"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The carrying out of the status, its dynamic aspect is?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Role",
      "B": "task",
      "C": "action",
      "D": "plan"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The simplest and largest class of society is",
    "options": {
      "A": "hunting",
      "B": "agrarian",
      "C": "horticultural",
      "D": "preindustrial"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Society is classified by social organization into",
    "options": {
      "A": "3",
      "B": "4",
      "C": "2",
      "D": "5"
    },
    "answer": "",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Technology made things feasible and",
    "options": {
      "A": "attainable",
      "B": "a fordable",
      "C": "available",
      "D": "achievable"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The destruction of nature is the destruction of",
    "options": {
      "A": "society",
      "B": "future",
      "C": "standard",
      "D": "quality"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Society and person are",
    "options": {
      "A": "interdependent",
      "B": "coexist",
      "C": "partners",
      "D": "dependent"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "As individuals, we worry --- about collective survival",
    "options": {
      "A": "more",
      "B": "often",
      "C": "less",
      "D": "regularly"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Humans are able to harness and control the forces of nature through?",
    "options": {
      "A": "personal opinions",
      "B": "education",
      "C": "modern technology",
      "D": "interaction"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Society is important for the -- of man?",
    "options": {
      "A": "existence",
      "B": "survival",
      "C": "positioning",
      "D": "making"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Human survival can only be accomplished if human beings act?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Co lectively",
      "B": "Co lected",
      "C": "unism",
      "D": "Together"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The largest social systemis of which state?",
    "options": {
      "A": "nation",
      "B": "human",
      "C": "social",
      "D": "vilage"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Auguste Comte conceived the word Sociology in?",
    "options": {
      "A": "1828",
      "B": "1838",
      "C": "1818",
      "D": "1819"
    },
    "answer": "",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sociology is a branch of which sciences",
    "options": {
      "A": "human",
      "B": "social",
      "C": "Agrarian",
      "D": "Bioscience"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The largest group of people inhabiting a specific territory is",
    "options": {
      "A": "People's court",
      "B": "Public",
      "C": "Community",
      "D": "Society"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The study of a society on a highly generalized or abstract level is done by the",
    "options": {
      "A": "Psychologists",
      "B": "Sociologist",
      "C": "Economists",
      "D": "Idealist"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sociology is a combination of --- and ---",
    "options": {
      "A": "Latin and French",
      "B": "Latin and Greek",
      "C": "Latin and Pidgin",
      "D": "French and France"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The intellectual discipline concerned with developing knowledge about human",
    "options": {
      "A": "life",
      "B": "existence",
      "C": "beings",
      "D": "relationship"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Goal is the prediction of behaviour and discovery of",
    "options": {
      "A": "truths",
      "B": "facts",
      "C": "ideas",
      "D": "image"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The largest social systemis the -- state",
    "options": {
      "A": "human",
      "B": "polarised",
      "C": "nation",
      "D": "society"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Growth of cities at the expense of rural areas is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "Urbanization",
      "B": "Population",
      "C": "Emmigrants",
      "D": "Expolsion"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The least complex class of society is",
    "options": {
      "A": "agarian",
      "B": "hunting and gathering",
      "C": "horticultural",
      "D": "industrial"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Preoccupation with rules and regulations as bureaucratic problemis reffered to as",
    "options": {
      "A": "Alienation",
      "B": "Ritualism",
      "C": "Inertia",
      "D": "Obligatory"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Factors employed in specialization that ensures the competence of employes is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Chain of command",
      "B": "Body of rules",
      "C": "Impersonality",
      "D": "Merit/tenure"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Factors employed in specialization that encourages equitability is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Chain of command",
      "B": "Body of rules",
      "C": "Impersonality",
      "D": "Merit/tenure"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Factors employed in specialization that defines the role androles of persons inposts",
    "options": {
      "A": "Chain of command",
      "B": "Body of rules",
      "C": "Impersonality",
      "D": "Merit/tenure"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Factors employed in specialization that encourages hierarchy of authority is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Chain of command",
      "B": "Body of rules",
      "C": "Impersonality",
      "D": "Merit/tenure"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Extra legitimate channels of communication in organization include the following except",
    "options": {
      "A": "Sharpness",
      "B": "Grapviness",
      "C": "Scuttle built",
      "D": "Rumour mils"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following are characteristics of formal organization except",
    "options": {
      "A": "Structure",
      "B": "Permanent",
      "C": "Heirachy",
      "D": "Generous"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The organization with upper limit of 50,000 members is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Sma l organization",
      "B": "Middle organization",
      "C": "Large organization",
      "D": "Giant organization"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The organization with upper limit of 1,000 people is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Sma l organization",
      "B": "Middle organization",
      "C": "Large organization",
      "D": "Giant organization"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The organization where key members can directly interact with all others is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Sma l organization",
      "B": "Middle organization",
      "C": "Large organization",
      "D": "Giant organization"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complex organization refers to",
    "options": {
      "A": "Sma l organization",
      "B": "Middle organization",
      "C": "Large organization",
      "D": "Giant organization"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which organisation does members knowthemselves",
    "options": {
      "A": "Sma l organization",
      "B": "Middle organization",
      "C": "Large organization",
      "D": "Giant organization"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The economic systemthat believed that individuals should think and labour for his country as whole is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Federalism",
      "B": "Capitalism",
      "C": "Socialism",
      "D": "Communism"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The economic systemthat believed that every man is entitled to the necessity of life is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Federalism",
      "B": "Capitalism",
      "C": "Socialism",
      "D": "Communism"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The economic systemthat came into being in western europe doing with industrail revolution is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Federalism",
      "B": "Capitalism",
      "C": "Socialism",
      "D": "Communism"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Latent function of education include the following except",
    "options": {
      "A": "Cultural integration",
      "B": "Custodial",
      "C": "Attitudinal",
      "D": "Stratification"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The obvious function of education include this",
    "options": {
      "A": "Cognitive",
      "B": "Innovation",
      "C": "Socialization",
      "D": "Moral"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "General goal of Education include the following except",
    "options": {
      "A": "Cognitive",
      "B": "Innovation",
      "C": "Socialization",
      "D": "Moral"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A common feature of religion is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Establishment of identity",
      "B": "Clarification of the world",
      "C": "Beliefs",
      "D": "Relief ot guilt"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of religion include the following except",
    "options": {
      "A": "Establishment of identity",
      "B": "Clarification of the world",
      "C": "Beliefs",
      "D": "Relief ot guilt"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Preoccupation with rules and regulations as bureaucratic problemis reffered to as",
    "options": {
      "A": "Alienation",
      "B": "Ritualism",
      "C": "Inertia",
      "D": "Obligatory"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Factors employed in specialization that ensures the competence of employes is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Chain of command",
      "B": "Body of rules",
      "C": "Impersonality",
      "D": "Merit/tenure"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Factors employed in specialization that encourages equitability is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Chain of command",
      "B": "Body of rules",
      "C": "Impersonality",
      "D": "Merit/tenure"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Factors employed in specialization that defines the role androles of persons inposts",
    "options": {
      "A": "Chain of command",
      "B": "Body of rules",
      "C": "Impersonality",
      "D": "Merit/tenure"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Factors employed in specialization that encourages hierarchy of authority is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Chain of command",
      "B": "Body of rules",
      "C": "Impersonality",
      "D": "Merit/tenure"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Extra legitimate channels of communication in organization include the following except",
    "options": {
      "A": "Sharpness",
      "B": "Grapviness",
      "C": "Scuttle built",
      "D": "Rumour mils"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following are characteristics of formal organization except",
    "options": {
      "A": "Structure",
      "B": "Permanent",
      "C": "Heirachy",
      "D": "Generous"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The organization with upper limit of 50,000 members is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Sma l organization",
      "B": "Middle organization",
      "C": "Large organization",
      "D": "Giant organization"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The organization with upper limit of 1,000 people is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Sma l organization",
      "B": "Middle organization",
      "C": "Large organization",
      "D": "Giant organization"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The organization where key members can directly interact with all others is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Sma l organization",
      "B": "Middle organization",
      "C": "Large organization",
      "D": "Giant organization"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complex organization refers to",
    "options": {
      "A": "Sma l organization",
      "B": "Middle organization",
      "C": "Large organization",
      "D": "Giant organization"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which organisation does members knowthemselves",
    "options": {
      "A": "Sma l organization",
      "B": "Middle organization",
      "C": "Large organization",
      "D": "Giant organization"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The economic systemthat believed that individuals should think and labour for his country as whole is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Federalism",
      "B": "Capitalism",
      "C": "Socialism",
      "D": "Communism"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The economic systemthat believed that every man is entitled to the necessity of life is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Federalism",
      "B": "Capitalism",
      "C": "Socialism",
      "D": "Communism"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The economic systemthat came into being in western europe doing with industrail revolution is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Federalism",
      "B": "Capitalism",
      "C": "Socialism",
      "D": "Communism"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Latent function of education include the following except",
    "options": {
      "A": "Cultural integration",
      "B": "Custodial",
      "C": "Attitudinal",
      "D": "Stratification"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The obvious function of education include this",
    "options": {
      "A": "Cognitive",
      "B": "Innovation",
      "C": "Socialization",
      "D": "Moral"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "General goal of Education include the following except",
    "options": {
      "A": "Cognitive",
      "B": "Innovation",
      "C": "Socialization",
      "D": "Moral"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A common feature of religion is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Establishment of identity",
      "B": "Clarification of the world",
      "C": "Beliefs",
      "D": "Relief ot guilt"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of religion include the following except",
    "options": {
      "A": "Establishment of identity",
      "B": "Clarification of the world",
      "C": "Beliefs",
      "D": "Relief ot guilt"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following are characteristics of A mass except \t,",
    "options": {
      "A": "Homogeneity",
      "B": "Anonymity",
      "C": "Poverty of interaction",
      "D": "Looseness of organization"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The terminal stage of social movement development is _,",
    "options": {
      "A": "Formalized Organization",
      "B": "Institutionalization",
      "C": "Social unrest",
      "D": "Popular excitement"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most initial of the social movement types is \t,",
    "options": {
      "A": "General Social movement",
      "B": "Expressive movement",
      "C": "specific Social movement",
      "D": "Revival movement"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The major social processes include the following except\t,",
    "options": {
      "A": "Opposition",
      "B": "Cooperation",
      "C": "Adjustment",
      "D": "Gratification"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sociology shares more fromthe following subjects except  ,",
    "options": {
      "A": "Economics",
      "B": "anthropology",
      "C": "Physiology",
      "D": "Psychology"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The levels of sociological analysis of social life include the following except \t,",
    "options": {
      "A": "Interpersonal",
      "B": "Group",
      "C": "Intergroup",
      "D": "Society"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "developed the concept of \"dramaturgy\"",
    "options": {
      "A": "George simmel",
      "B": "Pitirim Sorokin",
      "C": "Max Weber",
      "D": "Ervin Go fman"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "proposed that economics is the central force in social change",
    "options": {
      "A": "Max Weber",
      "B": "Karl Marx",
      "C": "Emile Durkeim",
      "D": "Herbert Spencer"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "proposed that organisms enolve overtime as they adapt to their environment",
    "options": {
      "A": "Emile Durkheim",
      "B": "Charles Darusin",
      "C": "Herbert spencer",
      "D": "Max weber"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "is known as the second founder of sociology.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Karl Marx Weber",
      "B": "Emile Durkheim",
      "C": "Max Weber",
      "D": "Herbert Spencer"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the approaches of sociology is concerned with \"what are the contemporary sociologists doing?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Analytical",
      "B": "Empirical",
      "C": "Pedagogical",
      "D": "Historical"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the approaches of sociology is concerned with \"what does reason suggest\"?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Analytical",
      "B": "Empirical",
      "C": "Pedagogical",
      "D": "Historical"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the approaches of sociology is concerned with \"what did the founding fathers say\"?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Analytical",
      "B": "Empirical",
      "C": "Pedagogical",
      "D": "Historical"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scientific and technological advances transformed the society fromthe \"manual\" way of life to what pattern of living?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Agricultural",
      "B": "Rural",
      "C": "Urban",
      "D": "Mechanized"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "had outstanding classical works done in sociology in the late 19th and early 20th centuries in France.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Karl Marx Weber",
      "B": "Emile Durkheim",
      "C": "Auguste Comte",
      "D": "Robert Strauss"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The famous phrase of Auguste Comte is   ,",
    "options": {
      "A": "To know, to predict and to control",
      "B": "To predict, to know and to control",
      "C": "To control, to know and to predict",
      "D": "To know, to control and to predict"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Agrarian society was reached around year \t,",
    "options": {
      "A": "5000BC",
      "B": "1000BC",
      "C": "2000BC",
      "D": "3000BC"
    },
    "answer": "",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The earliest and least complex society is \t,",
    "options": {
      "A": "Horticultural society",
      "B": "Agrarian society",
      "C": "Hunting/Gathering society",
      "D": "Preindustrial society"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "At the conception of sociology, the Belgian scholar who engaged in statistical studies of the society was \t,",
    "options": {
      "A": "Auguste Comte",
      "B": "Adolph Quatelet",
      "C": "Adolph Hitler",
      "D": "Cockerham"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The initial intention of Auguste Comte was to name sociology a \t,",
    "options": {
      "A": "Social statistics",
      "B": "Social Physics",
      "C": "Social Chemistry",
      "D": "Social Science"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who gave a line of demarcation pertaing to the content of sociology?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Auguste Comte",
      "B": "Herbert Spencer",
      "C": "George Simmel",
      "D": "Pitirim Sorokin"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Example of a Regulating/Restraining institution is \t,",
    "options": {
      "A": "Family",
      "B": "Religion",
      "C": "Politics",
      "D": "Economy"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Example of a Producing/Distributing institution is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Family",
      "B": "Religion",
      "C": "Politics",
      "D": "Economy"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Example of a Maintaining/Sustaining institution is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Family",
      "B": "Religion",
      "C": "Politics",
      "D": "Economy"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gemeinschaft society is best reffered fo as\t,",
    "options": {
      "A": "Traditional society",
      "B": "Formal society",
      "C": "Association society",
      "D": "Specialized society"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "All the following are basic to the society except",
    "options": {
      "A": "Family",
      "B": "Education",
      "C": "Polity",
      "D": "Durability"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary characteristic exhibited by a social institution is \t,",
    "options": {
      "A": "Family",
      "B": "Education",
      "C": "Polity",
      "D": "Durability"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of crowd can be described as ''aggressive crowd''",
    "options": {
      "A": "Casual",
      "B": "Conventional",
      "C": "Acting",
      "D": "Dancing"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gemeinschaft society is also known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "Traditional society",
      "B": "Formal society",
      "C": "Association society",
      "D": "Specialized society"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of crowd can be described as ''expressive crowd''",
    "options": {
      "A": "Casual",
      "B": "Conventional",
      "C": "Acting",
      "D": "Dancing"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of crowd can be described as ''people listening to concert''",
    "options": {
      "A": "Casual",
      "B": "Conventional",
      "C": "Acting",
      "D": "Dancing"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of crowd can be described as ''momentary assemblage of individuals''",
    "options": {
      "A": "Casual",
      "B": "Conventional",
      "C": "Acting",
      "D": "Dancing"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Argument and Counter-argument lead to the formation of",
    "options": {
      "A": "Regulation",
      "B": "Laws",
      "C": "Rules",
      "D": "Public opinion"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which level of sociological analysis is involved in slavery or aparthied system",
    "options": {
      "A": "Interpersonal",
      "B": "Group",
      "C": "Societal",
      "D": "Interractional"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which level of sociological analysis is involved in a university community interaction",
    "options": {
      "A": "Interpersonal",
      "B": "Group",
      "C": "Societal",
      "D": "Interractional"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which level of sociological analysis is involved in student-lecturer interaction",
    "options": {
      "A": "Interpersonal",
      "B": "Group",
      "C": "Intergroup",
      "D": "Society"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The social scientist who believed that sociology is the study of the content of human actions",
    "options": {
      "A": "Auguste Comte",
      "B": "Herbert Spencer",
      "C": "George Simmel",
      "D": "Pitirim Sorokin"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The social scientist who believed that sociology must take and digest all data studied is",
    "options": {
      "A": "Auguste Comte",
      "B": "Herbert Spencer",
      "C": "George Simmel",
      "D": "Pitirim Sorokin"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The social scientist who believed that sociology is was a super space",
    "options": {
      "A": "Auguste Comte",
      "B": "Herbert Spencer",
      "C": "George Simmel",
      "D": "Pitirim Sorokin"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who characterised sociological perspective as ''seeing the general in particular''",
    "options": {
      "A": "Auguste Comte",
      "B": "Herbert Spencer",
      "C": "George Simmel",
      "D": "Pitirim Sorokin"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  }
]